# Kristian Smith

## Junior Full Stack Developer

#### Contact

## Sköntorpsvägen 115,12053, Årsta, Sweden (+46) 763 55 96 32 <u>kristiansmith@me.com</u> Gthub - KristianDsmith Linkedin – Kristian Smith

## **Executive Summary**

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full Stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python. I have 20 years' experience in Restaurant and Hospitality. I am a driven valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving ability. Many years experience leading teams in multiple locations. Creative professional with diversified and extensive restaurant management, operations and marketing experience combined with supply chain and project management expertise. I am eager to enter the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

## **Education**

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development Code Institute -Dublin, Ireland

Sound Engineering and Production Ladbroke Grove Studios, City University, London

Music Business / Marketing and Law City University, London

NVQ Level 3 Food Production West Herts College, UK

NVQ Level 1 & 2 Catering & Hospitality West Herts College, UK

## **Experience**

*March 2020 – April 2023* Creative Director • Director • Curb Food

July 2019 – march 2020 Restaurant Consultent • Consultant • Krstian Smith Gastronomy

November 2019 – March 2020 Head Chef • Manager • Hobo Hotel

*March 2015 – June 2019* Lead Culinary Creative • Manager • Jay Dub Productions

March 2012 – June 2015 Chef • Flippin Burgers

*June 2011 – March 2012* Paternity leave

*April 2009 – May 2011* E-commerce Manager • Manager • Time W&J design AB

June 2004 – March 2009 Assitant Manager • Manager • SeOne London

#### Technical skills

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Python MySQL jQueery Bootstrap Github Wordpress

#### Professional skills

Organisational
Time Management
Creativity & Growth Mindset
Project management
Problem solving
Development
Management
Customer Service
Communication
Adaptability

#### Personal

Music & production Food & Wine Travelling & exploring Outdoors Active sports Meditation Healthy lifestyle

#### Languages

English - Mother tounge Swedish - Basic

## Selected experience

- Developed and launched food tech start up Curb Food valued at 30 million dollars and 200 staff within 2 years.
- Led the Development team in creating 15 restaurant concepts launched in Sweden, Germany, and Denmark.
- Implemented and optimized the kitchen design for improved efficiency based on data collected.
- Took the lead in setting up the supply chain network and development of products with Curb suppliers.
- Developed and implemented new restaurant concept Hobo XO.
- Developed the culinary concept for the restaurants Lådan and Dogfood.
- Development & completion of e-commerce website, brand websites.
- SEO Marketing to increase visitors & sales.
- Processing orders, payments, shipping orders and ticket sales.
- Development & implementation of social media marketing.
- Experienced in managing multiple teams from 5 to 60 people in different locations.

## Portfolio of projects

Wave - brand website for a an eco surf and yoga retreat in Portugal. Technologies Used - HTML5 , CSS.

GitHub - https://kristiandsmith.github.io/wave-project-1-official/

Tic Tac Toe Game – A simple designed two player Tic tac toe game. Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS with JavaScript.

GitHub - https://kristiandsmith.github.io/tic-tac-toe-project2/

Battleship Game – A simple designed user vs computer battleship game. Technologies Used - Python

Heroku - https://battleships-23-b994430075a8.herokuapp.com/

#### References

Available uppon request.